<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Palmdale Real Estate Podcast with Ron Hier</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The HIER Advantage - your professional Palmdale Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Ron Hier</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2020-11-24 17:36:04 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Ron Hier</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Palmdale, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>ronhier@thehieradvantage.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Ron Hier</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Ron Hier</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Palmdale, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Palmdale Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The HIER Advantage - your professional Palmdale Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Should Sellers Never Be Present During a Showing?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-should-sellers-never-be-present-during-a-showing.html</link>
        
        <author>Ron Hier</author>
        <pubDate>2020-11-18 10:59:23 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ron+Hier/Why+Should+Sellers+Never+Be+Present+During+a+Showing_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are four reasons why sellers should never be home during a showing.

Recently, I had an agent reach out to me and say, “Ron, my home seller wants to be home during showings. What should I do?” I told them that they shouldn’t want to be home during that time. Specifically, there are four reasons why a home seller should never be in their home when it’s being shown to a buyer and their agent:

1. Clients need to be kept safe from COVID-19. In this day and age, they may not want to be exposed to people they don’t know. With all the video and photography we have available these days, buyers will likely know what a home looks like before they set foot in it. You could require that all offers be made subject to a visual home inspection, but that would eliminate a bunch of buyers because the majority of them prefer to see a home in person before they make an offer. 

2. Buyers can feel pressured by the seller’s presence. They may feel like they can’t freely take a look around the home if the seller is wandering around or sitting in the living room watching TV. They may also have trouble visualizing themselves living in the home if someone else is doing just that right in front of their eyes. 

3. Sellers tend to want to bring attention to their home’s upgrades and how they’ve enjoyed them. The problem is, buyers may not see these upgrades the same way. Furthermore, showcasing any upgrades may come off as pushy, and buyers may feel like the seller wants them to pay more for the home than it’s truly worth. 

“It’s best if your seller is not home when you show their property to a buyer.”

4. Buyers (and their agents) ask questions. You don’t want them doing this to the seller directly or when you’re not present. The questions might begin innocently enough, but imagine this exchange for a second:

Buyer: “That’s nice flooring—how long ago did you have it done?”Seller: “Thank you very much! We had it done last year.”Buyer: “How soon do you plan on moving?”Seller: “As soon as I get an offer.”

The moment that the last line is spoken, your client gives away their negotiating power. Afterward, you can be sure that the buyer and their agent leave the house assuming the seller will take less because of how motivated they are to sell. You don’t want that. 

Buyers can be picky, and that’s okay, but if the seller is present during a showing and overhears the buyer singling out things they don’t like about the house or aspects they would change if they bought it, it can hurt their feelings. This, in turn, can make them hostile toward that buyer and result in a missed opportunity. 

Selling your personal residence is personal. That’s why we teach our seller clients to treat the transaction as a business transaction. What do business people do? They look at the bottom line, and the bottom line, in this case, is that it’s best if your seller is not home when you show their property to a buyer. 

If you have questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me via phone or email. I’d love to help you.


  

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ron+Hier/Why+Should+Sellers+Never+Be+Present+During+a+Showing_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ron+Hier/Why+Should+Sellers+Never+Be+Present+During+a+Showing_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are four reasons why sellers should never be home during a showing.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Ron Hier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are four reasons why sellers should never be home during a showing.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Palmdale, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Handle Requests for Repairs</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-handle-requests-for-repairs.html</link>
        
        <author>Ron Hier</author>
        <pubDate>2020-11-04 09:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ron+Hier/How+to+Handle+Requests+for+Repairs.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here’s how to make a request for repairs without ticking off the seller.

Recently, one of my agents came to me with some issues regarding the request for repairs on a property that had a home inspection done. Of course, the inspector was just doing their job—combing through the home and calling out issues concerning maintenance and possible code violations. The buyer then wanted the agent to put together a list of repairs, but that is a tad more nuanced than you might think; if the buyer gives the seller a laundry list of repairs to handle, the seller could cancel. Though sellers rarely do, they always have the power to back out, so we agents must find a tactful way to make clear the buyer’s requests and still preserve the deal. 

When given a list of repairs, a seller always has five options: 


  Do some of them
  Do all of them 
  Do none of them
  Draw a credit in lieu of repairs
  Make partial repairs and draw partial credit 


“Addressing repairs up front in your purchase agreement can save you a ton of grief!”

For buyers, it’s best to address the issue of repairs  in advance when you write your offer. In the purchase agreement, the buyer can proactively: 


  Limit the dollar amount in the request for repairs (e.g., “any and all repairs not to exceed $500”) 
  State that all inspections will be used for informational purposes only—nothing will be asked of the seller 
  Remove the inspection contingencies altogether (Warning: To justify this kind of risk, the house would have to appear to be in excellent shape)  


While each strategy has advantages and disadvantages, all are ways to get your offer accepted without killing the transaction in the inspection phase. Negotiations can be a little tricky, but what the buyer usually wants is for the seller to fix as much as possible without getting upset. Buyers are already in a tight market, and half the battle was getting their offer accepted. The last thing you want to do is irritate the seller to the point that they withdraw from the deal, leaving you back where you started—in a low-inventory, high-competition market. 

If you find that the home needs significantly more work than you thought it did, it may just be best to walk away from it. Thankfully, though, you’ll almost always be able to work out issues with the seller if you have the right approach. Remember: Addressing repairs up front in your purchase agreement can save you a ton of grief! 

Every case is unique; this information covers most of what comes up in routine home inspections, but not all. If you have questions on this or any other real estate topic, please reach out by phone or email. I’m always more than happy to have an in-depth chat with curious real estate agents about any matter. 


  

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ron+Hier/How+to+Handle+Requests+for+Repairs.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ron+Hier/How+to+Handle+Requests+for+Repairs.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s how to make a request for repairs without ticking off the seller.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Ron Hier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s how to make a request for repairs without ticking off the seller.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Palmdale, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Which Tips Will Help Get Your Offer Accepted?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/which-tips-will-help-get-your-offer-accepted.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        <author>Ron Hier</author>
        <pubDate>2020-10-15 15:20:06 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ron+Hier/Which+Tips+Will+Help+Get+Your+Offer+Accepted_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

These four tips will help your buyer come out on top in a bidding war.

Recently, one of my agents came to me and said, “Ron, how do I get my offer accepted? My buyers keep getting beaten out.” If you’re asking yourself the same thing, there are four main things you can do to elevate your buyer’s offer to the top of sellers’ minds. 

First, make sure your buyer is pre-approved by a local lender. When there’s a local lender involved, chances are good that local agents know them and have built trust with them. 

Second, put down a large deposit. Although most of the houses in our area are listed between $300,000 and $500,000, I’ve seen some people put down deposits as low as $2,500. That kind of a deposit won’t make your buyer look strong in a seller’s eyes. If they can put down a $10,000, $20,000, or even $30,000 deposit and write that into the purchase agreement, however, it’ll go a long way toward their offer getting accepted. 

Third, remove some contingencies. You need a very strong buyer to attempt this. One contingency they can remove, for instance, is the appraisal contingency. In a competitive market, the price of a home tends to get bid upward, so if your buyer is strong financially and has cash reserves, they can remove the appraisal contingency. 

“You have to look at the seller’s bottom line because that’s what they’re looking at when they have multiple offers.”

However, they should understand that this means they’ll have to make up the cash difference if the appraisal doesn’t match the agreed-upon sale price. If they can make up the whole difference, that’s great. If they can’t, they can still cover a portion of the difference. For example, they can agree to pay an extra $10,000 above the appraised value (not to exceed the agreed-upon sale price) if the appraisal comes in low. 

Other ideas for this tip include:


  Closing the gap in the contingency removal period. The default period is 17 days, so try shortening it to 10 days.
  Telling the seller that you’ll still order a home inspection, but you won’t ask for any repairs. 
  Telling the seller you’ll order a wood-destroying organisms report, but you won’t ask them to fix anything.


You have to look at the seller’s bottom line because that’s what they’re looking at when they have multiple offers: who’s the strongest, won’t cost them any money, can close on their terms, etc. 

Lastly, find out what’s most important to the seller. It may not be the highest-priced offer. They may need to do a rent-back or establish a 60-day escrow period. The only way to find out is to call their agent and find out what they want most. 

If you try these tips and still have a hard time getting your offer accepted, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you. 


  

</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ron+Hier/Which+Tips+Will+Help+Get+Your+Offer+Accepted_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Ron+Hier/Which+Tips+Will+Help+Get+Your+Offer+Accepted_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>These four tips will help your buyer come out on top in a bidding war.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Ron Hier</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>These four tips will help your buyer come out on top in a bidding war.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Palmdale, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Ron Hier</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Ron Hier</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The HIER Advantage - your professional Palmdale Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
